<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Joeri Nicolaes</title>
    <link>https://gourie.github.io/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://gourie.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Joeri Nicolaes</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Joeri Nicolaes, 2021</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 19:37:52 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://gourie.github.io/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Joeri Nicolaes</title>
      <link>https://gourie.github.io/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time to start writing</title>
      <link>https://gourie.github.io/post/starter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 19:37:52 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gourie.github.io/post/starter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During my long summer break I decided to start writing about my learnings on this website. Although I hope that my ramblings
are helpful for others, I have to admit that my motivations to do so are selfish:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you truly master a new concept when you are able to explain it succinctly in your own words&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have enjoyed reading over 85 papers in the last 2 years but lack an easy way to revisit my summary learnings
from these efforts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&#39;s time to practise my English writing skills a bit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you know &lt;strong&gt;why&lt;/strong&gt; I am adding more online content let&#39;s spend a minute to talk about &lt;strong&gt;what&lt;/strong&gt; I intend to write about.
The short answer is &amp;ldquo;anything that I studied recently in my professional sphere of interest&amp;rdquo;. This starts from computer
vision and may zoom in a lot on medical image analysis but I sometimes wander into methodology concepts that I fancy (e.g.
Variational Auto-Encoders and causal inference to name two of my current favorites).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, let&#39;s talk briefly about my sources. Most of my study material are scientific papers published on arXiv/journals and
papers or talks in conferences (e.g. MICCAI, ICML, NeurIPS, ICLR, &amp;hellip;) or in readings groups that I regularly attend.
You may ask how much I read and spend time studying new concepts, well much less than I would like but I try carving out
a few hours per week in my schedule.
I have tried following a &amp;lsquo;read two new papers every week&amp;rsquo; routine for a while, but I have abandonned this by now. I
currently follow my intuition browsing through the citation notifications that end up in my mailbox and diving into
some when I am able to free up some time. More importantly, I decided to increase the depth of my readings and spend
more time thinking about what I have read (favoring depth over breadth).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, I would like to ask you, the reader, a favour. Please reach out to me for questions or comments on my content.
I am specifically keen to find out whether my writings are clear and discuss your views or experiments with the discussed
content. Although this format is static and one-way, I would love to start a conversation with anyone interested!!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Detection of Vertebral Fractures in CT Using 3D Convolutional Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://gourie.github.io/talk/ects2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gourie.github.io/talk/ects2020/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detection of vertebral fractures in CT using 3D Convolutional Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://gourie.github.io/publication/nicolaes-2019-detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gourie.github.io/publication/nicolaes-2019-detection/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automated Detection of Vertebral Fractures in CT Using 3D Convolutional Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://gourie.github.io/talk/rsna2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 11:05:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gourie.github.io/talk/rsna2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Note: the video requires an RSNA virtual meeting subscription&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detection of vertebral fractures in CT using 3D Convolutional Neural Networks</title>
      <link>https://gourie.github.io/talk/miccai_csi2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 09:30:00 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gourie.github.io/talk/miccai_csi2019/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medical analytics and ethics</title>
      <link>https://gourie.github.io/talk/mitclub_march2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Mar 2018 16:45:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://gourie.github.io/talk/mitclub_march2018/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
